Hi.
In this lesson, you will learn how good-based indexing works in Kursor.
What it does, why it's useful and how it helps you search code-based using natural language.
By the end of this lesson, you will understand how Kursor tunes your entire workspace
into something you can talk to just like if you talk to CHI-GPT in this chart.
So, let's first open Kursor settings, Kursor settings, and go to indexing end dogs.
Cut-based indexing helps Kursor understand your project.
It's come all your files build a searchable map of your code.
And let's ask questions here in a chart like, I don't know, how this converter works
or what currency rate for this currency or etc.
So, you can use natural language questions, and it will analyze the code-based.
So, in the top, keyword search Kursor uses some semantic search under the hood.
It means it will understand the intent behind your questions.
So, you can ask not technical questions, and it will convert it to technical questions.
So, let's talk more about how it works.
When you open your workspace, Kursor quite the analyze all your files in the background
to your working on Stumpston, and he breaks them in biological pieces, like functions,
or glasses, and tunes each one in the mathematical fingerprint called embedded.
It's like a piece with some short and main information about this file.
This embeddings capture meaning not just words.
When you ask a question, Kursor compares your query with all these embeddings
to find the most relevant snippet across your code-based.
So, this is how it works.
Also, in the moment, it is about privacy and security.
So, you shouldn't worry, your code states private and secure.
File paths are always encrypt and your source code is never stored permanently and everything
stains in memory only while index is running.
So, Kursor deletes all temporary files and temporary data after processing.
So, your property remains safe, so don't worry about it.
So, as you see, I have five files, so I have five files, my five files index it.
You can delete index, you can think it if it's not seen, but Kursor automatically always
starts thinking when you add new files.
So, as you can see, you can index new folders.
So, if you don't like, you can disable it and all you added new folders
will be seen automatically.
You can also use ignore files, you'll talk about it in the next lesson.
What else is important? So, the traditional search tools like grep,
find exact matches and it's something more about how it works under the hood.
There can be some traditional search where you just search by word, like you search by react
and you, it tries to find the word react in your code.
But the magic search, it's something different. Like, if you, for example, say react,
it will understand a lot of words like react, technology, framework,
frontend, etc. For example, if you ask, where is my, imagine you have a big project,
yes, some dashboard project and you ask, so where is my navigation file?
And under navigation, you mean header file, for example.
And semantic search will understand it because it's similar words.
So, and this is how it works under the hood.
So, that's why is the combination of semantic storage and the normal storage,
it makes it faster to explore the watch code bases.
So, I hope it was useful and interesting to you understand about how code base
indexing the work. And once you start using it, you will navigate the origin, the reason
about you entire project much faster as and before.
So, but it's enabled automatically, so you will feel it already.
Okay, see you in the next two.